
   <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
     <channel>
       <title>Posts on Rafael Ribeiro</title>
       <link>https://rafaribe.github.io/posts/</link>
       <description>Recent content in Posts on Rafael Ribeiro</description>
       <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
       <language>en-us</language>
       
           <atom:link href="https://rafaribe.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
       
       
       <item>
         <title></title>
         <link>https://rafaribe.github.io/posts/hello/</link>
         <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
         
         <guid>https://rafaribe.github.io/posts/hello/</guid>
         <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;hello-world&#34;&gt;Hello World&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, world! Isn&amp;rsquo;t this the first program we all write when trying out a new programming language? I guess this makes it a cool title for this blog post as well.
This is my first post on my blog and as such I would like to introduce myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Rafael Ribeiro, I&amp;rsquo;m 28 years old and I like to work with computers.
I was born and raised in a small village in the Portuguese interior but since early I liked to play around with computers. At first to play games and at about 15 years of age, I found myself choosing a course for my 10th-year Secondary School which vaguely translates to the &amp;ldquo;Informatic Technological Course&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In there I had the first contact with programming, my first editor was Turbo Pascal? Remember that? It looked like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://rafaribe.github.io/img/hello-world/turbo-pascal-image.png&#34; alt=&#34;Turbo Pascal&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I know right? That&amp;rsquo;s grandpa&amp;rsquo;s code editor!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years have passed, we learned other programming languages, like C and PHP (this one sucks btw 😛), messed around with databases, and so on and a few years after going to college and getting into Computer Science,
I liked pretty much everything about it except the Math classes, but looking in retrospect they have their place and they are really valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, in college, I got contact with even more programming languages such as C++, C#, Visual Basic, Prolog, Lisp, to name a few, and also touched in other areas that I find interesting, such as networking and systems administration. I got into programming and started working for a company after finishing up my graduation and while taking a Master&amp;rsquo;s Degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I worked for three years in a single project, mainly doing C#, SQL Server, and being your Jack-of-all-trades, do everything kind of guy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve taken a new job since the beginning of the year and, by my choice, decided to embrace that inner sysadmin in me and leaned more towards a DevOps role in the company, dealing with cloud infrastructure, CI/CD pipelines and also programming, I didn&amp;rsquo;t stop programming.
It is an exciting thing for me. I&amp;rsquo;ve started learning and utilizing some exciting technologies such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prometheus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traefik&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cdk8s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Java with Spring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pulumi for Infrastructure provisioning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and many more&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also made me in love with cloud-native software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the other things that I&amp;rsquo;ve changed is my engagement with the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve attended some meetups and webinars like crazy the past few months, and they have proven to me to be such a valuable tool to learn new things, that I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine how I went all these past years without them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an exciting time, and launching this new blog I hope to share a bit of my experience with the community, do some tutorials and maybe help someone in some way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned ! 😎&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
       </item>
       
     </channel>
   </rss>
